Jordan Carlson

Mankato, MN | (507) 351-6026 | jordan.carlson.square@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/jordan-carlson99/ | https://github.com/jordan-carlson99
Active DoD Secret Security Clearance

SUMMARY

Hard working and dynamic veteran with 6 years of experience as an unmanned systems maintainer seeking career opportunities in the software and web development space. Relevant experience in integrating new technologies and performing configuration, deployment, and validation of real time data. Flexible problem solver with a strong record for achieving organizational goals through technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Front End | JavaScript , React.js, HTML5, CSS3, Promises, Async Code, AJAX, Vite, DOM API, jquery,
- Back End | Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, REST API Development, MVC
- Testing/Deployment | EC2, Docker, Render, pgbench, K6
- **Development** | Git, npm, TDD, Troubleshooting, Code Review, Continuous Improvement/Continuous Deployment, User Interface / User Experience, Unit Testing, RHEL
- Project Management | Agile Methodology, Scrum, Training & Development

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING APPLICATIONS

Nutrition App | https://github.com/jordan-carlson99/nutrition

- Developed interactive lightweight front end using pure CSS, vanilla JS, and direct DOM api manipulation allowing for low resource usage for use in austere environments on any hardware.
- Implemented lean relational database developed on a docker container using Postgresql with robust Express routing to minimize impact on content delivery performance for low end monolith servers.
- Designed SQL functions integrated into CRUD workflow separates front end concerns from database and backend concerns

Adidas Site Clone | https://github.com/FrontEndForceTeam/AdidasFEC

- Used agile methodology and team management to develop a one-for-one clone of an adidas shoe listing with dynamic data with 3 other team members.
- Directly managed team's git workflow as well as project sprint planning to ensure deliverable products and steady development within time constraints.
- Utilized React with react-router-dom for dynamic routing and page modularity along and lead development for monolith server back-end split out into component based psql queries for simple micro service refactoring.

EDUCATION

Operation Level-Up | Advanced Software Engineering Immersive, US Remote

2023

- 17-week software engineering immersive program with over 1000+ hours of coding.
- Full-Stack development with JavaScript, React, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and MySQL in an Agile environment

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Maintenance Team Leader | U.S. Army, Fort Campbell, KY

2021-2023

- Directly facilitated new technology integration with legacy systems enabling scalable data export, archival, and retrieval functions, improving final products and delivery to customers for 1,200 hours of video data.
- Mentored and trained employees on best practices, quality of work, and personal development.
- Performed network administration duties overseeing 5 independent networks and managing over 300
 user accounts on RHEL5 and RHEL6 RAID5 systems and windows server 2016 networks.
- Developed proficiency in my organization in satellite communications, basic Linux command line tools, and network troubleshooting.

Unmanned aerial systems maintainer | U.S. Army, Fort Campbell, KY

2018-2023

- Conducted technical evaluations, write-ups of deficiencies, and hardware and software corrections to the Shadow V-2 and Block3, Puma LRTA and LE, and Raven B platforms
- Managed and tracked system hours, uptimes, planned maintenance, and assisted in planning of mission sets that directly generated actionable intelligence that lead to strategic mission success.